Preliminary Inventory of the Jeb Stuart Magruder Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Jeb Stuart Magruder papers,
1968-1975
78043
Magruder, Jeb Stuart, 1934-
27 manuscript boxes, 2 oversize boxes (12 linear feet)
Hoover Institution on War, Revolution, and Peace Stanford, California 94305-6010
Diary, writings, correspondence, office files, memoranda, reports, sound recordings, and printed matter, relating to the elections of 1970 and 1972 and the Watergate hearings.
Administrative Information
Access
Box 1 closed.
Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives Audiovisual Specialist for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired.
Accruals
Increments may have been received since this finding aid was prepared. Please check Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/ to find the full extent of the collection.
Biographical Note
Special assistant to President Richard M. Nixon, 1969-1971; deputy director, Committee for the Re-Election of the President, 1971-1972.
Scope and Content Note
Diary, writings, correspondence, office files, memoranda, reports, sound recordings, and printed matter, relating to the elections of 1970 and 1972 and the Watergate hearings.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the repository's online public access catalog.
Subjects
Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-; Presidents--United States--Election--1972.; Watergate affair, 1972-1974.; Conservatism.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Politics and government--1969-1974.
Genres and Forms of Material
Video tapes.; Phonotapes.
Container List
- Records obtained by the Watergate Special Prosecution Force of the U.S. Department of Justice through a grand jury subpoena and subsequently accessioned in the National Archives (Record Group no. 460). (Box 1)
  Photocopies
  - Diary ("The Brooks Brothers Diary")
  - Grand Jury summons, 1973 May 15
  - Memoranda
  - Daily schedule, 1971
  - Airline ticket, 1973 February 14
  - Daily schedule (incomplete), 1972
  - Hotel bills, 1972
- Political campaign notebooks (Box 2)
- Book manuscript. (Box 3)
  Photocopy
- Office files
- Seven audiotapes (6.35mm x 540m) of the Watergate hearings, 1973 June 14 (Box 4)
- One color videotape, "Nine in the Morning," WTOP-TV, Washington, D.C., 1975 February 24
- Campaign mailings, 1972
- Office files (Box 5-16)
- Campaign notebooks (Box 17-19)
- Printed material and campaign posters (Box 20)
- Campaign notebooks and mailings (Box 21)
- Campaign notebooks, 1971 (oversize) (Box 22)
  - Middle America (one volume)
  - Spanish speaking voters (one volume)
- Campaign posters and charts (oversize) (Box 23)
- Correspondence (Box 24-27)
- Correspondence (Box 28)
- Phone Center Chairman's notebook, n.d.
- Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 29)
- Demographic surveys
- Maps and geological surveys for coastal regions of the U.S.
- Miscellany related to real estate development in South Carolina
- Three reels of microfilm of Jeb Stuart Magruder's testimony before the United States Senate Select Committee on Presidential Campaign Activities, 1973 June 12